啊！
做個purpose。
係，係。
喺度，噉你呢個就係。
嗰啲問題帶出嚟啲問題。
關於依個今日嘅請你哋嚟。
建議你點執行嗰啲建議，點去改善。
講個speech有冇啊？好啊，好啊！我哋主要係誒一一呢個。
短問短答，咁咧，你哋就向我哋解釋。
就畀你哋大多數時間，除除咗我哋問嘅問題。
呢個報告，審計處做關於你哋嘅誒呢個工作。
我哋就係睇緊第七號、七十四號審貴處報告第六章，就係關於呢個誒破產管理局。
係破破產及清盤嘅工作喺度，咁咧呢個今日我哋咧就唔係普通嘅誒public hearing，誒我知你身上又你未未未誒冇咩經驗喺我哋，今日我哋純粹咧就得半個鐘頭字八個字。
我哋今日個主打就係啊嘅議員喺度，咁大多數時問題佢都係從佢嗰度出嚟㗎啦嚇。阿樺，你可以介紹下呢個呢個。我理解局長好似有個speech佢想，局長有個speech，我又唔係好想去講個speech。你介紹咗人，我畀佢。
proceeding即係今日咧，都係一個誒比較創新嘅方法咧，就係時間好短嘅啫，就針對翻有關審計署報告咧，我哋希望有啲澄清嘅，亦都係一個誒或者少少嘅機會，我哋可以touch base傾下偈，瞭解下嘅情況。誒當然我哋唔排除有需要嘅時候咧，可能要有個full一個full hearing嘅，但係因為時間所，
下咧，我哋希望可以先瞭解咗少少問題先，希望唔需要去到一個full hearing噉。咁希望嗰啲answers question answers可以比較短嘅情況之下，大家瞭解初步噉樣好嘛？噉我如果你有需要介紹一下你誒，我哋希望儘快可以處理咗咯，嗰個介紹工作先。好誒，局長你有個發言稿，我希望你。
嗯。
講其實係有幾多咧？咁睇唔到，因為真係呢個係未知數。咁但係我都盡可能咧提升我哋工作效率咧，可以快啲去應付嘅。
拯救程序咧，同埋嗰個跨境無力償債呢兩方面嘅，噉就嗰個法定個企業拯救程序嗰個草案咧。
盡快處理。好，好，好，好。噉啊，多謝啊啊Abraham同埋Paul同埋啊Kenneth畀嘅機會。其實我哋好歡迎今次呢個聆訊嘅，即係等我哋有機會，包括我同事啊Felix啊，同埋嚟回應一下審計署呢份報告。咁審計署嘅報告入面咧，就係好多嘢都提咗好多意見咧。其實整體嚟講咧，我哋都接受嘅。
咧其實從我個角度咧，主要呢兩個兩個法例，咁但係另一方面係牽涉到一啲具體嘅一啲嘅誒feas方面工作咧，一陣佢都會回應嘅。咁誒，我簡單咁回應下。多謝。多謝曬你。阿波。我哋想唔想聽埋O.R.嘅opening speech先？好。方便我哋睇嘛？啊，對唔住。
咁睇翻，其實大家都知道啦嚇。誒破產管理處依家負責嘅工作咧，主要under係cap三啊二啊、cap六啊呢啲噉樣類似嘅工作。噉我哋都知道，其實隨住呢個上年個社會事件嚇，同埋依家呢個疫情咧，其實之後可能嚟緊一啲破產，無論個人啊或者企業啊，都可能會多嘅。咁但係具體嚟，
咁喺從我局方角度咧，我盡可能係畀支持、畀資源。咁誒，我哋誒阿菲力嘅隊伍咧嚇喺火山管理處嘅工作之下咧，能夠咧係更加好噉樣發揮佢哋嘅效能啊。咁具體啲嚟講，其實我覺得有兩方面咧，我可以講翻就係誒，除咗阿菲力先生會提到嘅關於一。
破產清盤服務嘅管理工作嘅一啲誒建議嘅回應之外咧，係牽涉到局方嘅主要係一個立法方面嘅問題嚇。咁喺呢方面，我可能講上兩方面嘅工作啦。咁第一咧係關於話嗰個無力償債法律條文方面咧，審計處嘅報告入面咧係講咗兩樣嘢嘅。第一就講緊法定企業嘅情。
其實我哋已經進入咗後期階段㗎啦，嚇！咁大家都知道咧，其實阿坡都知道，其實呢個法律嘅嗰個誒草案比較複雜，嚇，牽涉好多細節咧。咁同埋咧牽涉，嚟包括啊公司自己啊、誒債權人啊、嚇僱主啊、僱員啊等等一大堆嘢，董事責任啊等等。咁所以其實我哋依家咧過去幾個未來幾個月咧，就會同我哋相關的。
去傾嘅就其實最關於啲牽涉到呢個立法嘅建議同相關嘅條文。噉我哋目標咧嚇就係希望咧係計劃喺二零二零到二一年個立法年度咧就係向立法會提交嗰個條例草案嘅。咁至於嗰個跨境無力償債咁叫做cross border boundary嘅cross border呢方面嘅立法工作咧。
We aim to implement the recommendations by the end of this year.
包括 where the assets involved are landed properties.
監督私鑑理師或P.I.P.s，我會稱他們為，和未來的發展。我會簡要地逐一討論每個領域。
合作從破產是 not always readily forthcoming， and there is a considerable level of case administration required in these cases even after discharge or the case is put on the release programme.
by the end of July, the aim, if possible, of putting them on release programme by December, and if this can't be achieved, they will all be referred to the CAM meeting for consideration by the directorate team.
Additional categories of assets. We want to continue to provide regular updates on common legal problems, refine in-house approval limits for specific actions, continue with our investment in staff training and experience sharing amongst teams at management level, and give case-specific advice where necessary.
聽大家知道咧都比較複雜啲嘅嚇，咁依家其實我哋誒都研究緊點樣係將呢啲嘅相關嘅立法工作咧，可以擺喺本地法例嘅可能性。咁其實咧，我哋睇過一大輪一啲嘅參考咧，其實係依家目前大部分地方咧都係採納咗嗰個聯合國國際貿易法例委員會嘅示範法個model law。
咧作為基礎咧，係作為本地嘅跨境勞力常製法嘅基礎嘅。咁呢一方面，其實我哋揾咗會研究嗰個顧問嘅意見咧，同埋都會徵詢翻持持份stakeholders意見咧。咁希望進一步噉就會睇下點樣係將呢個model law咧係變成一個本地嘅立法咧，係可以咧喺呢方面咧係加快立法工作嘅。咁最後。
誒，佢哋仲有今日或者佢唔係好清楚，佢哋仲有多個speech from呢個ORO。I see，OK，噉你聽聽下，冇意思。好啊。Thank you, Chairman and Members. Good afternoon. Thank you, Director of Audit, for your report. And as Secretary said, we agree with the recommendations.
By way of a letter to this committee on one st of June, we have also provided a detailed response to the twenty one further questions that this committee has put for official receiver. At the outset, can I please provide some context on our work? The work and functions of official receiver are governed by statute.
And necessary procedures for the most part are required by legislation, and as such, refinement of process has constraints. Since the Asian financial crisis in ninety eight, the number of insolvency cases has remained at a comparatively high level, and given the accumulation of cases. Sorry, I can hear it in my own ear. Yeah.
Given the accumulation of cases and the need to administer each bankruptcy case for at least four to eight years, the workload of a official receiver does continue to increase. The issues arising in each case are different, and there are various degrees of complexity.
refinement of process, re-engineering and simplification of procedures are ongoing. We have employed temporary staff where necessary and made use of outsourcing schemes over the years to assist us with the heavy workload. The director of audit has made recommendations in respect of the administration of our in-house insolvency services. Our
In respect of the six recommendations for enhancement of administration of in-house insolvency services, we have set out at some length in our letter the strategies that we already have in place to assist our officers in expeditious resolution of difficult issues. But whilst we have explained that the cases are varied, complex and
And don't always lend themselves readily to standard solutions. With resolution, for the most part, being dependent upon further investigations and requiring the cooperation of third parties. So these are matters sometimes outside of our control. But that said, we will continue to work and develop and refine effective strategies that can be rolled out generally.
We're in the process of again reviewing common difficulties that hold up cases, and will promulgate further guidelines in addition to those already in place. And we anticipate this review to be finalised by the end of this calendar year. We intend to expand specific further no further action thresholds in respect of additional categories.
Apart from general guidelines and refinement of the case management processes, we will continue to provide bespoke guidance and assistance at case level at our monthly case administration meetings, or CAM. We will continue more generally with the quarterly bankruptcy account meetings as well. Both of these meetings we have established since 20.
2018， they comprise a team of our director officers and we aim to identify and progress and monitor the long outstanding complex cases， particularly those that have got a larger bankruptcy account balance， and these meetings have proved very successful， we intend to expand this CAM meeting to consider issues.
with a view to conducting quality audits from April 2021.
The preliminary proposals to consolidate the current four registers into one, and this will be implemented from July.
我們會繼續審視我們部門的科技實施，並確保成本和效益是對齊的。
In respect of the six recommendations made on the way forward for the office, the secretary has responded on the legislative initiatives.
And in respect of checking accounts submitted, meantime, a review of our risk-based strategy mechanism is underway and is expected to be finalised by the end of July.
Structures on a regular basis and ensure alignment and maximum efficiency for delivery of our service. But we will complete a full strategic review by March 2021.
Changing insolvency environment and the difficulty in predicting volume, rationalisation of the fee structure is not easy. That said, we aim to finalise our review by March 2021.
We anticipate having a more robust framework for monitoring BIPs in place by September 2020, and with the implementation of our ESS in due course, we anticipate further enhancement of our regulatory capabilities.
措施已經被內置以確保目標覆蓋範圍由財務服務團隊進行現場審計將會達成，我們打算審查和加強對不滿意行為的報告，以及審查和加強現有的報告和維持各種投訴登記冊。
which are also holding up the pre two thousand and two company liquidation cases that were identified by the director of audit in the report. The pre two thousand and two personal bankruptcy cases are already reviewed by this meeting, but we have also instructed since the report that a list of all cases be compiled with directions for review.
The long outstanding cases identified by the director are complex. For instance, one case is a listed holding company with subsidiaries in insolvent liquidations in other jurisdictions. Closure of the Hong Kong liquidation is dependent upon dividends being received from these overseas subsidiaries. These cases are still active.
We have set out other difficulties that we face in our letter to the committee. We will nevertheless use our best endeavours to complete these old complex cases as soon as possible. We aim to move ahead robustly with renewed focus. And apart from the disposal of landed properties, which we anticipate will take a longer time to resolve.
In respect of the eight recommendations made for the monitoring of the PIPs, the private insolvency practitioners, steps are being taken to conduct quality audit of panel T scheme PIPs. The detailed procedures and logistics are under consideration, and they will be ready by September 2020.
According to our records, 92% of liquidators' accounts were submitted within six months of the account end date, and those outstanding accounts identified by the director represent about 3% of accounts submitted over the same period. We will be reviewing and enhancing the follow-up action required in relation to these outstanding accounts.
In respect of submission and checking of accounts, we have actually been in the process of reviewing our various practices. At the moment, issuance of warning letters is centralised, but it's followed up by individual case officers. So we're considering a more efficient strategy to follow up the warning letters. Furthermore.
Approval in principle has been given for funding for an electronic submission system. We're planning to seek funding approval from Finance Committee later this year. Once implemented, this system will allow e-submission of accounts by the PIPs. This should greatly enhance efficiency.
In relation to the perceived underutilisation of the individual voluntary arrangement process in the Hong Kong context, we will continue to engage our stakeholders and explore opportunities to facilitate the use of such procedures where appropriate. We will continue to review our manpower needs, resources and operation.
The review of fee structures is in fact at a relatively advanced stage, but there are challenges in all jurisdictions in devising an alternative fee structure to support a self-funding insolvency service of last resort, given the widely fluctuating insolvency numbers. The average.
啊！多謝原嘅問題，多謝局長。
誒，我哋喺錢啊、人方面邊位答策略方面？Mckenna。
就係嗰個關於誒跨境嘅誒個問題咧，個個例點解會喺譬如我哋應該講緊係二零。
好啊！誒，喺嗰個將來嗰個誒應付嗰個就嚟緊嘅高峯期咧，你哋嘅資源上有冇咩諗法？
嘅過程就會比較順暢啲，就唔會咧重複咗喺十幾年前咧喺立法會嗰度係即係得唔到誒立法會支持嘅嗰個即係誒失敗嘅經驗。咁呢個係我哋而家嗰個計劃。好，唔該，許生波。
有二萬六千多嘅破產嘅惡案咧，誒而家講緊嚟緊高峯，其實嚟緊。你哋好似舊債未清，新債又嚟緊，好多噉。咁呢度你有冇咩資源上、策略上、人手上會處理？係兩個問題，我想要同局長講講先。唔該，局長。
好誒，多謝阿Paul。咁其實誒喺呢個問題上面咧，我都好同大家一樣嘅，即係希望想快啲完成嗰個有關第一類嗰個法例。因為其實都之前講過喺二零一五年講過話要做啦。咁依家其實我哋嚟緊喺二零二零二一年咧諗住做嘅。咁具體嚟講，我同事阿Sam可以再補充下嘅。
Chairman and Members, I thank you for your time, and I thank the Commission for the recommendations, which will undoubtedly provide fresh perspectives and guidance for us in the reviews that we will undertake in implementation of the recommendations. And my colleague and I would be very pleased to answer Members' questions. Thank you. Thank you, Ms. McNamee, for the.
22 paragraphs reply to us is actually answer many of the questions that we we will be raising. In fact, I'll leave it to our lead member, the honourable Paul J, to start the questions. Paul, thank you, Chair.誒，首先我多謝審計署，因為佢咧今次。
呢一個報告咧，令到咧好似一個黑洞裏邊咧，突然間有啲光照落去噉樣。因為好多年咧，似乎都冇知道究竟成個破產管理處係做緊啲咩工作。但係睇翻好簡單一個一個impression咧，就係一個印象咧，就係似乎誒好多嗰啲話會做嘅嘢咧，或者諗住做嘅嘢都喺翻二零二零年發生嘅，即係以。
知就話，如果冇呢一個審計處嘅一個誒主動去查一查咧，似乎就好多嘢都唔會喺發生緊噉。呢個呢個感覺啊，呢個印象，我先講講先咧。新政局長牽涉嘅其實係政策上就唔多嘅，局長嚇。雖然你係新上任啦，但係都當然呢個係你誒一個portfolio裏邊嘅一個範疇，但係最關注當然喺你個角度咧。
一五年已經開始講緊話要立例，二零一七年本來會上會嘅，搞到而家二零二零年啦，都仲係要再攞時間。咁呢個第一個，咁可能要或者你都輕解解咧。第二個就係話你哋誒諗住喺人手方面誒點樣咧？因為大家都知道喺二零零二年嘅高峯期，對對唔住有成萬。
誒，我諗誒，剛才阿謝議員問到嗰個誒法律嗰個建議咧，係有關企業拯救嗰個啦。嗰個係我哋二零一五年嘅時候咧，就做咗一輪嘅誒諮詢，同埋咧就同誒業界咧係有討論。誒，如果大家記得咧，就其實呢個喺立法會都唔係一個誒新嘅議題嚟嘅。
我哋喺誒上世紀初嘅時候，上上世紀尾嘅時候，其實已經喺立法會嗰度咧試過幾次係提出呢個企業請購嘅誒法案。咁當時個經驗都唔係好成功。噉我哋喺二零一五去到二零一七誒嗰兩嗰兩年嘅嗰誒嗰個過程裏邊咧，就係誒我哋將一啲舊嘅議題誒。
重新思考，亦都同一啲誒持份者咧，就係誒作咗啲深入嘅討論。但係嗰個誒共識嘅程度咧，亦都我哋當時嘅評估就係，亦都未去到話我哋可以重新將個法案提上嚟立法會嘅階段。咁所以，我喺二零一七年之後咧，就係再作咗誒幾個喺個法律草案上邊嘅誒反省同。
同埋修改，咁而家我哋嗰個階段咧，就係我哋有一個新嘅法案，係條完整嘅新法案咧，係已經係準備會誒帶上嚟立法會。誒，正如局長所講咧，我哋嗰個時間表咧，就係希望喺下個立法年度誒開始嘅時候咧，我哋就誒盡早可以咧帶誒草案上嚟立法會度做審議工作。噉我哋而家呢個階段咧。
亦都唔想浪費咗時間，所以咧就誒嗰個法案嘅草擬稿，我哋其實咧喺下個星期咧就會陸陸續續誒伴隨住一份政策文件咧，我哋會將佢發放畀誒誒各界嘅持份者，包括誒會計界啦，包括誒法律界啦嘅持份者，我哋都會發放畀。
唔識，唔識。
但嗱個delay嘅問題，噉我請有少少機會問一問咧。
首先，我想了解下咧，你哋講話有啲誒。
你哋嗰個其中四個scheme裏面，其中一個嘅計誒，關於係誒債務人。
After four years, oh sorry, so we actually are quite efficient in.
叫做做咗你要做嘅嘢，但係對於個破產者嚟講咧，都仲係要等好耐咧，先至可以攞到個release order from court。係，變為特別。
I can answer that question, but I'm I'm not sure if my translation is correct. I mean, it's the trustee who is released, not the bankrupt. I don't know. Let's say the trustee, in terms of the trustee, so releasing the trustee's custodianship of all the assets. Well, how long would it normally take, and what is the delay like?
佢哋，我就希望咧喺六月、七月、八月呢幾個誒月份裏邊咧，我哋可以再同主要嘅持份者咧有個好仔細嘅討論。若果大家喺誒嗰個制度誒嘅設計同埋啲條文嘅細節上邊係個共識程度高啲咧，噉我哋下一個立法年度將個草案帶上立法會嘅時候咧，可能嗰個審議。
Thank you. Yes, thank you for that question. We are very keenly watching the figures. There has been a lot of information in the press about a tsunami of cases coming into the office, but we are not seeing that as yet. The figures that we have coming in, the petitions that are being
Whilst there's a slight rise, there is not a huge increase that has been observed. The numbers are a little bit difficult to ascertain because of the closure of the court. The court is necessary for the filing of the petitions, so we're still monitoring very keenly to see what the situation is actually going to be.
But we are fully prepared for an increase, and we have been taking the opportunity to refine our processes. We have a fast track team set up, which will try and deal with cases with absolutely nothing to do very, very quickly and efficiently and effectively. We intend to make use of the
Anti-epidemic funding to take on board some temporary staff. We have got a recruitment process in place at the moment, and we will enhance the capability of our team members by putting in place some new additional staff to help them with the numbers that are coming.
所以， at this stage, I would say that we are fully equipped to deal with what is coming, and we will continue to look at steps that we can take to refine process and make savings and efficiencies where we can. Thank you. Thank you, Paul. All right, something我都要申報，因為講起 insolvent嗰part咧，我哋律師行都係呢。
誒申請破產嘅其中個scheme嘅五五個P.I.P.裏邊，其中一個P.I.P.嚟嘅嚇，噉我要申報啲利益先。誒，但係我亦都可以同時咧，因為我呢個經驗咧，可以分享多少少個困難，因為我理解到咧，而家其中一個最大嘅爭議就係嗰個誒成建所有成個破產過程或者清盤過程嗰個時間。
有個叫做誒release program啦，你哋譬如講破產先算啦嚇，噉啊簡簡易程序嘅破產咧，你哋如果有資產可以誒或者派誒誒realize嗰啲咧，你希望就係誒十八個月啦。如果冇嗰啲咧嚇，亦都冇咩monthly contribution嗰啲咧，噉我哋係嗰個expect expectant嘅。
時間係十二個月咧。我想理解下呢一個噉嘅時限咧。我哋當然知道係好多時都做唔到咧。但係what exactly mean你嗰個擺在個release program之後係咪等於破產嗰個破產者就已經係清咗咧，定還是其實只不過係你哋喺喺你個部門裏邊咧係？
Interestingly, we have just done a comparative analysis of the cases which we deal with in-house and the cases which are undertaken by our PIPs, and it is clear that our office are considerably more efficient than the outsourced PIPs. We have a quite a strong. We have a seventy of our cases are released.
睇。
Just my suggestion, Chairman.
tight to control on on those PIPs, but one one one thing which is quite a general you know or ignorant question is.
Getting our cases released, release is release by the trustee. And when a PIP is released, if there's any assets that still require to be realised or dealt with, they come to us because we are always the trustee of last resort. So once a trust, an outside trustee is released, he can walk away from the case. He's finished.
anything that comes up thereafter, I will have to deal with. Our office will deal with. So we can't just get released if there is still work that has to be done. But in terms of the bankrupt himself, he will not. He will be discharged after four years, and he will continue with his obligations for four years. So conceivably, there could.
still be after acquired property there could still be he could get a job he could get income there could be contributions so that is why I said in my opening remarks these are not just numbers you know these are cases that come into our department to be administered for a period of four years the issues can be complex they can arise at any
Time and so is it is a challenging exercise. As I'm sure you have as the under member, I'm sure you understand. It is a challenging challenging exercise to deal with these cases as if they're just numbers, because each case can have its own complexities and difficulties, and they can arise at any time. So I think.
That's why we pointed out quite clearly in our letter to the committee that whilst we do have an 18 month target, we use it in house to monitor the progress of our cases. We they're brought up to our monthly management meetings. The cases are before the assistant.
official receiver who will see that they are at least being progressed systematically and properly, and that there's nothing. It's kind of complainer complier explain. If it's not met the 18 month target, why has it not met the 18 month target? Is it reasonable? So it is a consistent monitoring.
監察過程，和它不是一件容易的工作，而是一個挑戰性的任務。我感謝你對這一點的認可。我覺得，我哋兩個聽你問兩個嘢，你先wrap up好冇啊？快啲wrap up啦，已經。我只係開始，一個啦，下一個啦。唔緊要，我哋會可以跟進。Never mind。
哦，Thank you, Mr. Chairman. I I read through the official receiver's speech in particular, paragraph fourteen to sixteen, concerning the late submission of the accounts prepared by the PIPs, and I understand that you are going to implement.
I understand that. I mean, these PIPs, some of them are accountants, some of them are lawyers. But under the present regime here in Hong Kong, you don't really necessarily need a qualification to become a PIP. Is my understanding correct? And how, if that is the case, how do you choose?
Who is a qualified PIP to do your outsourcing job, Ms McKenna? Thank you for that question. That is correct. We don't have a licensing system in Hong Kong, which other jurisdictions do have. We, under our tender scheme, our requirements are they have to be a lawyer, an accountant.
或一公司 secretary，所以這些係 The Three Qualifications That or The Professions That We Identify， But Equally Under Each Of The Tenders There Is Quite Specific Criteria About Experience Required Number Of Staff Required Experience In Doing
Particularly complex cases in the panel A scheme, for example. So it's monitored at that level. We look at these cases and we put out to tender, and we will make sure they do have the pre-qualifying qualifications. Yeah, I, Mr. Chairman, I do want to remind or suggest to the.
perhaps a kind of standard course at least should be devised in future for these practitioners to attend. I mean, I'm not advocating exam as such, but at least they should attend courses and have those hours credited before they can do those things. This is
嗯。
When we talk between each other, sorry, chairman, we cannot answer.
Scheme, if you may, we're certainly happy to look at. When I tell you to answer, then you answer. Sorry, because the control meeting.
perhaps I welcome certainly your answer to my last question, which I think will be very helpful to shorten the the wait for the for the people involved. Now, one other question is.
To be doing much worse than the department itself. In particular, with reference to the answers to questions one and two, or basically one, the supplemental questions, it would appear that.
Bankruptcy cases were signed out to the PIPs, and bear in mind what you said about the the sort of figures that you you've been holding about the the time for the release programme or what have you.
get from our presentation. We've also put a lot of effort into trying to help them with the complex cases, because there is difficulty in having a one-size-fits-all guidelines. themselves are not really
哦，Thank you, Chairman. It's certainly something we can consider. I don't know if we can actually release these for public consumption, but we can certainly consider doing some sessions, some some training sessions where we where we prepare to answer questions and share some of our.
Okay, any more question, Ken? That's all. Okay, thank you. Paul, well, Madam Vice President, I appreciate your answer to my last question regarding the relatively more efficient handling of the cases within the department. What I have in mind though is, why is it that the outside practitioners seem
There references were made to internal reference and internal circulars as such provided by the or within the department itself to help your own people or petitioners in dealing with these cases. Maybe that's the reason really why you said the.
The in-house handling of the cases are far more efficient than outsiders. Would that be the answer? I must say that this is only looking at the release statistics. I think there are many benchmarks for what is a successful completion of a liquidation case. Percentage of dividend that goes to creditors.
Prosecution investigations, there could be many benchmarks. So my efficiency target was very much on release, so being released from the cases that are under review. And I just want to make that clear. I'm not suggesting in any way that we are much better, but it is just a statistic that is quite useful.
For us as a department to benchmark ourselves against what's going on outside, but we do and we have since certainly since I became official receiver. And previously, we do put quite a lot of emphasis on training our staff so that they do know what they're doing. And as I hope you.
That of course we have to have them, but they're not the answer to everything. We invest a lot of time training our staff, managing our staff and supporting our staff through the complications of some of the administration difficulties. Paul, well bear in mind that up to twenty five percent of the so-called debtor petitions summary.
Would it be fair to say that if the department or the OL can share some of the resources, some of the circulars and advices that you have circulated internally to those BIPs, they would might assess the the shortening of the handling process of the entire.
techniques and tactics that we've developed over the years. I don't think that would be a problem. Right. That's actually a follow-up on my colleague, Hon. Bukendt's question about the qualification or training of the PIPs before they are sort of given the task. Actually, quite difficult tasks and very technical tasks too. So.
for the。
time needed.
Next one幾快喎嚇！
Again, thank you for coming. Thank you. Thank you, Chairman. Thank you, members.
I don't know whether you have kept any statistics regarding the, the.
It's something you can, you said. But have you done that before? If not, why not?
the discharge of the trustee from from so the court's scrutiny.
Form sheets, which we will be chase after your department to ensure that they comply to all the recommendations made.
total release or the release of the trustees from the from the handling of the whole process as well as just the like what you said, we know normally the the the time for the bankruptcy period is standard for and in some cases eight years, but in terms of the release programme or
Would the cost waiting time be one of the issues that bother you and/or Ms. McKenna? Chairman, thank you. Yes, I think that seems to be something that we are hearing from a lot of practitioners that the it is a court application, it is a court process, and I understand that it can take some time for these applications to.
Have steps been taken with the judiciary to sort of expedite the processing of these cases, Ms. McKenna? Chairman, thank you. We can certainly take up in our liaison meeting with the judiciary. We have regular meetings with the judiciary, and it's certainly something that we can put on the agenda.
Miss McKenna, thank you, Chairman. I am not sure if it's something that we've specifically raised. Normally, there's many issues dealt with at these sessions. I'm sure it has been something that has been discussed in the past. But with this very specific request, I'm very happy to put it on the next agenda.
Okay, I have to wrap up the the session again. Thank you very much for coming, Corby. To the extent that you have come well prepared and that that helped to save quite a lot of time of your 22 paragraph reply. Again, we look forward to writing to you if we have further.
question which I'm sure Paul will drop some question for you later. That we will be looking into your reply and looking into how you achieve the recommendation made by the director board. That over the years when you have the whole exercise completed, we have follow.